GEGHAM KHACHATRYAN

Middle Technical support engineer

+374-43-81-71-00

kgegham@outlook.com

LinkedIn

GitHub

LeetCode

SUMMARY

I am a technical support engineer with 4 years of experience. My work in technical support has provided me with valuable experience in customer service, including effective communication and problem-solving skills. I have also learned how to work collaboratively as part of a team and manage my time effectively. Since I studied programming at university for 6 years, I want to change my area of work and continue to develop my programming skills and use them to create high-quality software products. I am looking for a team where I can learn from experienced colleagues, collaborate on complex projects, and use my knowledge to achieve successful results.

EDUCATION

Synopsys Armenia Educational Department

Master of Science | Sep 2021 - Jun 2023 Specialization: Software Engineering

Synopsys Armenia Educational Department

Bachelor of Science | Sep 2019 - Jun 2021 Specialization: Software Engineering

State Engineering University of Armenia

Bachelor of Science | Sep 2017 - Jun 2021 Computer Systems and Informatics Department

SKILLS

- C/C++, Python, Basic Java
- STL, OOP, Data Structure
- · Algorithms and their complexity
- Basic QT Framework
- · Basics of multithreaded programming
- Templates
- · Git, GitHub
- · PowerShell, Bash
- Windows, Linux
- Virtualization, Containerization
- Jira, BMC Remedy, ServiceNow

FAMILIAR WITH

- Unreal Engine 4 and 5
- Jenkins, GitLab
- Selenium
- Docker
- AWS, Microsoft Azure
- Terraform, Ansible

LANGUAGES

- Armenian -Native
- · Russian Full professional proficiency
- English Limited working proficiency

HOBBIES

- · Game dev
- Play football
- Play AAA Games
- Snowboarding

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Technical Support Mid

Synopsys, Yerevan, Armenia | Feb 2023 - present

- Participate in IT projects to provide PowerShell automation support and meet project objectives.
- Develop and maintain PowerShell scripts to automate routine tasks such as installing certificates, adding to groups, changing user policies, and fixing recurring issues.
- Collaborate with cross-functional teams to identify automation opportunities and implement solutions.
- Provided technical support to end-users on desktops, laptops and mobile phones issues, including hardware and software troubleshooting.

IT Technical Support Junior

Synopsys, Yerevan, Armenia | Sep 2021 - Feb 2023

- Worked with new employees and set up new equipment for them
- Repaired hardware as necessary and work closely with service vendors to ensure continuity of service.
- Provided comprehensive support, problem resolution, and navigational assistance for customers via chat, email, and phone.
- Collaborated with the Logistics and procurement teams to purchase new hardware.

IT Technical Support Intern

Synopsys, Yerevan, Armenia | Sep 2019 - Sep 2021

- Resolved issues related to Windows, network connectivity, as well as problems associated with software and hardware errors.
- Configured hardware, devices, and software to set up workstations for employees.
- Assisting users in person and remotely with hardware-related concerns.